星际之门之亚特兰蒂斯 前情提要
Previously on Stargate Atlantis.
这不会是一个风暴
It can't be a storm.
它占据了整个地平线
It stretches across the whole horizon.
它至少覆盖了星球20% 的地区
This must cover 20 percent of the planet.
如果你不想有人伤亡,那就得把他们弄出去
If you want everyone to live,
you gate them off world.
之后的一个小时内,Atlantis里只会有不足10个的人
而且大部分都是科学家.
Within the next hour, there will be
less than 10 people on atlantis.
我们不能错失这个机会.
We cannot afford to pass up this opportunity.
我们无法开启防御系统的唯一阻碍是什么?
What is the one thing keeping us from having a shield?
电力
Electricity.
Atlantis的设计是足以经受闪电的袭击的
Atlantis is designed
to withstand substantial lightning strikes.
城市中到处都有避雷针.
There are lightning rods all over the city.
如果我们停止地下站
If we disable the grounding stations,
无庸怀疑，我们就可以使用这些能量
that energy could conceivably be used
来给我们的护罩发生器补充能量
to charge up the shield generators.
我们决定待在探险者2号里面
等风暴过了再回去
We decided to wait out the storm in the jumper.
据我所知
一小队Genii武装力量闯了进来
From what I can ascertain,
a small Genii strike force has gated in.
为什么这么做?
Why are you doing this?
你们拥有我们非常需要的东西
You are in possession of supplies we vitally need...
C-4炸药, 以及你们所有的药品
the C-4 explosive, all of your medical supplies.
现在...我们控制了 Atlantis.
As of right now, we are in control of atlantis.
跟Weir博士告别吧.
Say goodbye to Dr. Weir.
现在的结局是...
And now the conclusion...
Kolya!
Kolya, 不要这么做!
Kolya, don't do this!
这对获取你所需要的有什么帮助么?
How is this going to help you get what you want?
这是让Sheppard给逼的, 不能怪我
Sheppard put you in this position, not me.
你不能这么做. 这太疯狂了. 你需要她.
You can't do this. This is crazy. You need her.
她是对的, 司令官
She's right, commander.
启动防护罩需要密码
There are codes required to activate the shield,
只要她知道这个密码
没有她, 你将无法启动防护罩
codes that only she knows.
You can't do it without her.
没有我你也不能
You can't do this without me either.
我的意思是, 我们是一个有机的整体
I mean, we're a package deal.
如果你把我们之间的这种平衡打破
You take us out of the equation,
你将不会得到有一个好的收场的
and you don't have an end-game.
要知道, 这就像是一个棋局
Granted, that's a chess term.
我的意思是只有我们可以修好地下站
My point is we're the only ones
who can fix the grounding station.
只有我们可以启动防护罩
We're the only ones who can activate the shield.
也只有我们可以解决那些无法想像的问题
We're the only ones that can
solve problems I can't even think of yet.
你只要杀死我们当中的任何一个
You kill either one of us,
你就不会得到你所想要的
and you don't get what you want.
这就是我们的重要性
That's how important we are.
Rodney.
Rodney, 他知道了
Rodney, he gets it.
多谢你的...
I appreciate your...
你对我们完成此次任务还有用
You're an asset we need to complete this mission.
你为了我站在一支枪的前面
You stepped in front of a gun for me.
现在先不忙谢我
Don't thank me just yet.
离风暴来临只有两个半小时了
除非我们运气绝对好
We've got two and a half hours till the storm hits,
and unless our luck changes drastically,
这座城市将被湮没
this city is going to be obliterated.
Sheppard少校, 你相信么
Major Sheppard, how's this for credibility?
Weir死了
Weir is dead.
我要杀了你
I'm going to kill you.
也许吧
Maybe.
别挡我的路, 要不McKay也会去跟她做伴
Stay out of my way, or McKay will join her.
星际之门之亚特兰蒂斯
第一季第11集 暴风眼
Season 1 : Episode 11 The Eye
这太令人惊奇了
This is amazing.
你过来
There you are.
我们在这儿
We're here.
让两个人到那去
Take two men, head there.
下面四层
Four levels down.
那是Sheppard.
That's Sheppard.
是的,长官
Yes, sir.
我们走
Let's go.
你留在这
You're with me.
他正走出走廊
He's heading out of the hallways.
- 终于来了
- 就是它
- Holy Grail
- That's it!
你在做什么?
What are you doing, man?
调节惯性阀, 给我们的飞船增加点重量
Adding weight to the puddle jumper
by resetting its inertial dampeners.
你不该动它
我们已经足够重了
You shouldn't screw with those controls.
We're heavy enough.
难道不能再小心一点么?
Can't be too careful.
是的, 你行. 我想你是过于小心了.
Yes, you can. You can be way too careful.
我们不可能被吹走的
There's no chance we're going to blow away here.
够了
Let it go.
这应该够了
That should be enough.
风暴还要持续多久?
How much longer until the storm passes?
我想可能一半还不到
I guess we're barely halfway through,
但我没法告诉你
but there's no way to tell.
你知道, 我也希望他们都还好
You know, I hope they're okay, too.
怎么了?
What's this then?
风暴过去了?
We're through it?
不会
We can't be.
那是不可能的
It's not possible.
他在动
He's moving.
你肯定我们确实应该在这一层么?
Are you sure we're on the right level?
他到哪里去了?
Where did he go?
他会听到你那愚蠢的问题的
He can probably hear your stupid questions.
Oh, 你想来看看么?
Oh, will you look at this?
现在, 它已经...
Now, that is just...
这再也不能用了
That is never going to be useful again.
我想我应该可以接一个旁路
把整个开关绕开
I should be able to bypass
the switching station entirely.
很好, 这要多久?
Good. How long?
实际上这比看起来的要糟得多
It's not half as bad as it looks.
我想最多15, 20分钟吧
I'd say 15, 20 minutes tops.
干吧
Do it.
Weir博士, 我需要你来...
Dr. Weir, I need you to...
好的, 当然
Right, of course.
把那按住
Keep that there.
我们在风暴眼中
We're in the eye.
是的
Right.
一定是
Has to be.
风暴眼?
The eye?
风暴的正中心
Dead center of the storm.
风暴在周围旋转
这是一个20到40公里宽的区域
The storm swirls around
a 20- to 40- kilometer-wide area.
那就是说, 这种宁静不会持续下去?
Then this calm will not last?
当然, 实际上, 大约只有10分钟
No, in fact, in about 10 minutes,
马上就又会变得非常糟糕的
it's going to get very ugly again.
好的, 来吧
我们必须去帮助少校
Well, come on. We have to help the major.
我们可以起飞, 但是降落将会非常困难
相信我
We can take off, but landing is twice as hard,
believe me.
那如果风暴到达atlantis又将会怎样?
What if the storm's reached atlantis?
它到了么?
Has it?
现在还没有, 不过随时会到
Not just yet, but it will anytime now.
不要浪费时间了. 我们走, 我们走吧
Stop wasting time. Let's go. Let's go.
我们仍然必须穿过风暴, 中尉
这太疯狂了
We would still have to fly straight
through the storm, lieutenant. It's insanity.
这不是疯狂
这是一艘太空船
This is not insanity. This is a spaceship.
我们可以飞到风暴上面
We can fly up and over.
一直上去然后再下来?
Straight up and down?
一直上去然后再下来
Straight up and down.
我只是一个普通的医学博士, 不是一个魔术师
I'm a bloody medical doctor, not a magician.
我们可以做到
You can do it.
Teyla?
如果我们可以帮助, 那我们就必须去
If we can help, we must.
Oh, 我认输
Oh, crap.
20英尺远
20 feet away.
5英尺
Five feet.
这里的烟太多了
There's so much smoke.
哪边?
Which way?
你们在他的正上方
You're right on top of him.
是么? 如果他在我应该可以看到他
Yeah? I think I would see him if I was.
不要动
Stand by.
看见他了么?
Do you see him?
抓住他了么?
Did you get him?
报告
Report.
司令官
Commander.
是的, Sora.
Yes, Sora.
Ladon让三个人进行搜索行动
Ladon had been leading three of our men
on a reconnaissance mission.
看起来 Sheppard 少校又杀了我们三个人
It seems major Sheppard has killed
three more of our strike team.
告诉所有人回到控制室
Tell everyone to move back to the control room.
马上, 长官
Right away, sir.
你为什么告诉他你可以在15到20分钟内
把这个修好
Why did you tell him you could have
this fixed in 15 to 20 minutes?
Oh, 我不知道
Oh, I don't know.
也许这样他就不会杀了我们
Maybe so he wouldn't kill us.
我能理解, 不过一旦防护罩运作起来
I understand that, but once the shield is operational,
我们将不再有用
现在, 我们该怎么办?
we won't be very useful, now, will we?
那你为什么让我告诉他我可以在15到20分钟内把它修好?
Why did you let me tell him I could fix it in 15 or 20?
你必须跟他再拖延一下时间
You just have to stall him some more.
好, 我刚刚告诉它修好这个要多久
Well, I just told him how long it'll take.
那就在它身上再找一个问题
Find another problem with it.
告诉他们能量循环接口
Tell them that the power loop interface
无法与你的工作配合, 之类的
isn't jiving with your walkabout, something.
"无法配合"?
"Isn't jiving"?
Rodney, 我就是这个意思
Rodney, you get my point.
根据现在的情况来看
Though from the sounds of it,
如果我们给Sheppard足够的时间
if we give major Sheppard enough time,
他应该可以解决剩下那部分人
it seems like he can take care
of the rest of them on his own.
呼叫Cowen首领
Radio chief Cowen.
告诉他派出增援部队, 一整个连
Tell him to send reinforcements, a full company.
如果你们希望Sheppard少校
If you 're hoping major Sheppard
可以让我们减员, 那就想错了
can diminish our numbers, you are mistaken.
OK. McKay将要做什么?
Okay. What would McKay do?
你的切入有点陡了, 博士
You're coming in a little steep, doc.
- 谢谢你, 中尉
- 我对这非常清楚
- Thank you, Lieutenant.
- I'm very aware of that.
我告诉过你不要玩那些惯性阀
I told you not to play with the inertial dampeners.
我非常确信我已经把它们都拨回去了
I'm pretty sure I got them back where they were.
你为什么不尝试联系一下少校?
Why don't you try to contact the major?
首先, 你必须让我们先进去
First, you got to get us in there.
你到底要干什么?
What are you up to?
他做了些什么?
What's he done now?
我本该预料到的
I should have seen this coming.
司令官
Commander.
Sheppard少校切断了控制室的电源
Major Sheppard has cut power to the control room.
他是怎么做的?
How?
Atlantis的电力由5个小型发电机提供
Atlantis is being powered by five small generators,
每个独立的为城市中的一部分供电
each responsible for a separate area of the city.
Sheppard刚刚停掉了
Major Sheppard has just disabled
为星际之门控制台供电的那台发电机
the one generator that powers
stargate operations in this tower.
现在, 我们仍然可以进行一些主要的操作
Now, we still have most primary operations.
但我们完全失去了所有的次要的系统
We have definitely lost all secondary systems.
你还可以跟踪到Sheppard么?
Can you still track Sheppard?
不行
No.
那我们现在不知道他在哪了?
Then we have no idea where he is now.
是的, 长官
No, sir.
控制室安全么?
Is the control room secure?
是的, 长官
Yes, commander.
我建议让一些人去守住剩下的那些发电机
I suggest we send some men to guard
the remaining generators.
不行!
No!
他正想把我们分开, 这样好逐一消灭
He's trying to divide us into manageable numbers.
守住星际之门的控制台
Just hold stargate operations
直到增援赶到
until the reinforcements arrive.
明白
Understood.
如果他问起是什么要干这么久
If he asks what's taking so long,
你就去告诉他刚才所说的, 好么?
you have to do all the talking, okay?
你会没事的
You'll be fine.
不, 不, 我不会
No, no, I won't.
我干骗人这行不行
我不会去冒险的
I'm a terrible bluffer.
I've lost small fortunes at poker.
我的眼睛会跳. 笑起来也不自然.
这都不好
My eye twitches. I laugh inappropriately.
It's not pretty.
进行得怎么样了?
What's our progress?
我们碰到了一点小麻烦
We've hit a small snag.
正在进行诊断
We're just running a diagnostic
以确定它可以正常传送我们的编码
to make sure we can interface our codes properly.
只是一个小麻烦, 小麻烦
It's a small snag, small snag.
好的, 听着, 最多半个小时
It's, like, half an hour at the most.
司令官, Sheppard刚刚停掉了另外一个发电机
Commander Sheppard has just disabled another generator.
是的, Ladon, 我知道了
Yes, Ladon, I am aware of that.
他切断了三号地下站的电源
He's cut the power to grounding station three.
这还能修好么?
Can it still be repaired?
没有电? 不行
Without power? No.
没有它, 计划可以完成么?
Can the plan be completed without it?
其他三个地下站已经停掉了
The other three grounding stations
have been disabled.
不, 不行, 这还不够
No. No, it's just not good enough.
看, 断开地下站
Look, by uncoupling the grounding stations,
这意味着当闪电击中这座城市的时候
it means that when lightning strikes the city,
电能将无处可去
the electricity will have nowhere to go.
如果我对这些电能加以合适的引导
If I could channel the electricity properly
它将会穿过城市中的走廊
through the conduits that line the city corridors,
我们也就可以给防护罩提供能量...
we should be able to power the shield...
临时性的
Temporarily.
如果这些地下站当中只要还有一个仍然接在上面
If any of these grounding stations are left active,
那么大量的电能
a sizable amount of electricity
就会通往地下, 我们也将没有防护罩
will find its way to ground and no shield.
司令官, 风暴并没有放慢脚步
Commander, the storm has not slowed its pace.
我们没有时间了, 必须立即让防护罩工作起来
We have little time to get the shields activated.
我们应该重新评估我们的目标, 或许
We should re-evaluate our goal. Perhaps.
我们仍然有足够的时间来实现我们的目标
We still have more than enough time
to complete our objectives.
所以, 我强烈建议
Then I must strongly advise
让人去修好那些停掉的发电机
that we send men down to repair
the deactivated generators
并且守好剩下可以工作的那几个
and to guard the remaining active ones.
同意, 兵分两路
Agreed, teams of two,
但我要你守好控制室
but I want you to watch over the control room.
直到增援到达
As soon as the reinforcements arrive,
并带领他们以压倒性的力量抓住Sheppard
have them take Sheppard with overwhelming force.
明白
Understood.
或许等一下我们就可以处于防护罩的保护之下了
Perhaps we can be under shelter while we wait.
到时我一定会感冒...
I'm liable to catch a cold like that...
我认了
I take it that's a "no."
呆在这儿, 不要动
Remain here and be still.
我会回来接你们的
I will return for you.
我们要去哪?
Where are we going?
军械库
Armory.
你确定...
Are you sure...
你知道, 你总是在说你不是一个军人
You know you're always saying you're not military,
- 你没有必要服从命令?
- Hi.
- you don't have to take orders?
现在你必须听我的
Now you do.
就当是暂时性的
So long as it's temporary.
我们现在应该尝试联系少校么?
Should we try to contact the major now?
Genii可能正在监听我们的频率
The Genii may be monitoring our frequencies.
我不想通知他们我们已经到了
We do not want to alert them of our presence.
生命信号探测仪
Life-signs detector.
这些小点不会告诉我们谁是谁
These wee dots don't tell us much about who's who.
我们怎么知道谁是少校?
How do we know which one's the major?
如果有个小点除去了其他的点, 那就是他
He'll be the dot getting rid of the other dots.
棒极了
Great.
大概会来多少人?
How many should we expect?
一整个连, 60人或者更多
A full company, 60 or more.
如果没有这么多人过来
I don't know how we were expected
我们的处境就很难预料
to take a facility this size with any less.
我们本来的计划只是进行一次突袭
找回本该属于我们的东西
It was supposed to be a raid
to retrieve what was rightfully ours.
跟我来
With me.
来吧
Come on.
司令官, 增援到了
Reinforcements are arriving now, Commander.
让他们守住星际之门操作台
Have them secure stargate operations
然后向我汇报
and report back to me.
是, 司令官
Yes, Commander.
警戒这片区域
Secure the area.
然后我要你们...
Then I want you to...
把它关掉. Ladon!
Shut it off. Ladon!
阻止他!
Stop him!
我是Sora.
This is Sora.
停止发送增援
Stop sending the reinforcements.
星际之门的防护罩已经打开了
The stargate shield has been raised.
Sheppard打开了这个防护罩
Sheppard has raised the gate shield.
把它关掉
Shut it down.
Turn it off.
我不知道怎么关
I don't know how.
Ladon已经晕过去了
Ladon is unconscious.
把程序告诉她
Tell her the procedure.
不行, 我不知道他做了些什么!
I can't. I don't know what he's done!
告诉她
Tell her.
好吧, 他肯定是输入了他的个人命令码
Well, he must have entered
his personal command code.
是什么?
What is it?
我不知道!
I don't know!
只有Sheppard自己知道
Only Sheppard would know it.
相信我, 我没有那个胆
Trust me, I'm not that brave.
如果可以, 我肯定会帮你的
I would help you if I could.
你有那个命令码
You have the command codes.
没有用
It's no use.
已经完了
It's over.
门已经关上了
The gate has shut down.
不会再有人进来了
There are no more men coming.
有多少人过来了?
How many men made it?
五个
Five.
60人中的5个
Five of 60.
如果你想要这个城市, 你仍然需要我
You still need me if you want the city.
你仍然需要我们
You still need both of us.
他输入了某种安全码, 关掉了星际之门
He's entered some sort of security code
to lock down the gate.
给我一些时间
Just give me some time.
我应该可以破解它
I should be able to crack it.
快干
Do it.
司令官?
Commander?
他说他可以修好星际之门
He thinks he can have the gate fixed.
Athor的儿子通过了星际之门么?
Did Athor's son make it through the gate?
谁?
I'm sorry?
他的名字叫Idos.
His name is Idos.
他过来了么?
Did he make it?
没有, 长官
No, sir.
死掉了60多个人
Over 60 men killed.
保卫他的家园和他的人民
司令官, 正如我们期望的
Defending his home and his people,
Commander, as we would.
什么时候更多的增援能够发送过来?
When can more reinforcements be sent?
这需要时间, 大概一个小时
It will take time, perhaps an hour.
无法接受!
Unacceptable!
是的, 司令官, 这无法接受
Yes, Commander, it is unacceptable,
因为到了那时, 我们将会完全处于风暴之中了
because by then, we will be
in the full force of the storm.
也许会更快
Probably sooner.
Sheppard少校, 我有一个建议想告诉你
Major Sheppard, I have a proposition for you.
你听得出来这是谁的声音么?
Do you recognize that voice?
不
No.
Kolya, 我干得很辛苦啊
现在的分数是多少?
Kolya, I'm having a hard time keeping up.
What's the score again?
我的人告诉我你不仅仅停掉了
一些至关紧要的发电机
My men have informed me that not only have you disabled
而且还偷走了一些关键组件
some crucial generators,
but you've stolen key components
没有它们, 发电机就无法重新运转
which make it impossible for them to be restored.
是的, 是我做的
Yeah, I did that.
你的计划有两个缺陷
There are two flaws in your plan.
我非常乐意接受一些建设性的批评
I'm always open to constructive criticism.
第一, 你假装让我相信
你宁可毁掉这个城市
One, the assumption I would believe
也不愿让它落入我们之手
是非常幼稚的
you'd rather destroy the city
than let it fall to us is childish.
听起来不像是我
Doesn't sound like me.
第二, 如果并且当我意识到atlantis无法救回时
Second, if and when I determine atlantis unsalvageable,
Weir博士和McKay就会不复存在
doctors Weir and McKay become obsolete.
Weir还活着?
Weir is alive?
McKay博士曾经尽了很大的努力让她活着
Dr. McKay was able to make
a strong case for keeping her alive.
让我跟她说话
Let me talk to her.
Sheppard
Sheppard.
我们都在这里
We're both here.
很高兴听到你的声音
It's good to hear your voice.
是的, 很高兴能听到
Yeah, it's good to hear.
在风暴完全到达之前
我们只剩下不到一个小时了
We have less than one hour
before the storm hits full-force.
如果十分钟内, 三号地下站的电力仍然没有恢复的话
Weir将会死去
If the power is not returned to grounding station three
within the next 10 minutes, Dr. Weir dies.
又, 你是说?
Again, you mean.
他的死将会让你获得另外10分钟
Her death will buy you another 10 minutes,
在那之后, 如果电仍然没有来
McKay博士也会死
after which, should the power still be out,
Dr. McKay dies.
然后你将会和我们一起
直到这个城市被摧毁
We will then leave with what we can,
and the city will be destroyed.
不行, 时间太短了
Well, that's not enough time.
如果你不介意毁掉Atlantis
If you don't mind destroying atlantis,
那么就在接下来的20分钟里, 呆在你现在所在的地方
stay where you are for the next 20 minutes.
现在开始
Starting now.
不要带得太多
这样就跑不快了
Don't load up so much.
It'll slow you down.
没人再来两个弹夹
Two extra magazines each.
好的
All right.
你拿那做什么?
What do you need that for?
我会朝任何移动的东西开枪
Anything I see moving is going to get shot.
那么, 如果那时少校呢?
So, what if it's the major?
那么它只会被击昏枪打中, 而不是p-90
Then he'll get hit with a wraith
stunner instead of a p-90.
如果他先看到我们呢?
What if he sees us first?
他可能会先听到你
He'll probably hear you first.
你是在告诉我又该住嘴么?
Are you telling me to shut up again?
再一次
Again.
好吧
Right.
我们走
Let's go.
哪台发电机会给第三地下站供电?
Which naquadah generator would power
the third grounding station?
你在问我?
You're asking me?
不管是哪台, 那里肯定有伏兵
Whichever one it is, it's going to be an ambush.
不过我们仍然要去
We've got to be there.
那里有一个
There's one here.
- 你是猜的么?
- 是的, 不过我感觉就是
- Is that a guess?
- Aye, but it makes sense.
这是最近的
It's the closest.
好吧, 我开路
All right, I'll take point.
Teyla, 你殿后
你...
Teyla, you're on our six.
You...
我没有叫你就不要张嘴
Don't open your mouth until I say so.
只朝我告诉你的目标开火
Only shoot at what I tell you to shoot at.
你没有必要这么认真
You don't have to be so bloody pushy.
这是命令
That's an order.
停
Stop.
瞧, 你们老板要我把这玩意儿装回去
Look, your boss wanted me to turn this thing back on,
我看我们应该照他说的去做
so I think we should do what he says.
住嘴
Be quiet.
Sora.
我们抓住他了
We have him.
别杀他
Keep him alive.
我正过来
I'm on my way.
难道不是这个?
Is it the wrong one?
是的, 我正想这么说
Yeah, I'd say so.
噢, 你该不会是在谴责我吧
Oh, don't you blame me for this.
我不是工程师
I'm not an engineer.
对于Rodney和他的团队如何配置电源
I really only have a basic understanding
of how Rodney
我也只有一些最基本的印象
所以, 不要指望我...
and his team configured the power,
so don't expect me...
你能不能不说了, 好么?
You just can't stop talking, can you?
我只是自己停不下来
不管我说的是什么...
You just can't help yourself.
No matter what I say...
你这个伙计这么年轻
And you're such a nice young lad
现在却在那里发号施令
你这个厚颜无耻的小同性恋
until you're put in charge, you cheeky little bugger.
等等...
Wait...
如果这个站点是对的
那么少校就是还没有让他恢复?
What if this is the right station,
and the major has not made it back yet?
噢, 她是对的
Oh, she's right.
不, 不, 这个发电机在工作
No. No, this one's working.
还有多少时间?
How much time?
两分钟
Two minutes.
现在有5个发电机
There's five generators.
不是这个
It's not this one.
也不是给控制塔提供能量的那个
It can't be the one that powers the control tower.
现在剩下三个
That leaves three.
我们现在要从三个中把正确的那个选出来
We've got a one in three chance
of guessing the right one.
我们可能正在步入真正的埋伏
We may just be walking into the very ambush
我们正在试图将他从那里救出来
we're trying to save him from.
我们离一个传送器不远
We're not far from a transporter.
有哪个发电机离传送站比较近么?
Are any of the generators near a transport station?
是的, 有两个
Aye. There's two.
好的, 我们走
Well, let's go.
OK, 如果我没记错的话...
Okay, if I remember correctly...
好好想
Remember correctly.
它们在这里和这里
I think they are here and here.
你确定哪个是靠着发电机的?
Which one are you sure is next to a power generator?
- OK, 给我一点时间
- 没时间了, 快选一个
- Okay, just give me a moment.
- No moments. Pick one.
如果选错了, 你又要怪我
I'm the one you're going to blame if it's wrong.
我们现在必须动身了
We have to go now.
这儿
Here.
我可不想成为一个被囚犯
I don't mean to be a bad prisoner or anything,
不过如果我不按时把这个放回去
but Kolya is going to kill one of my people
Kolya就会杀死一个我们的人, 所以...
if I don't get this thing back on in time, so...
转过身来
Turn around.
你们转过身去
You turn around.
什么?
What?
好吧, 如果我必须转过身来, 那你们也要转过身去
Well, if I have to turn around, you should turn around.
该死的你们怎么现在才来?
What the hell took you so long?
- 嗯, 还不是因为外面那个风暴...
- 好了, 别说了
- Well, there's this storm...
- Just hold that thought.
看来Sheppard不想你死
It seems major Sheppard wants you to live.
我们接着干活吧
Let's get back to work.
你还好吧, 长官?
You okay, sir?
比刚才好多了
I've been better. Been worse.
我的肩膀有点疼
My shoulder's a little sore.
要我看看么?
Do you want me to take a look at that?
等现在这事搞定之后再说吧
I'll take a recheck when that'll be out.
我们应该离开这里
更多的Genii马上就会过来的
We should leave this area.
More Genii will be on their way.
太同意了
I couldn't agree more.
如果还是不能工作...
If this doesn't work...
它会工作的
It will.
我只是说, 如果它不能工作...
I'm just saying, if it doesn't work...
它会的
It will.
我相信它会的
但仍然有可能他不能工作...
I'm sure it will,
but in the unlikely event that it doesn't...
Rodney...
求你了
Please.
妙极了
Fantastic.
噢, 感谢上帝
Oh, thank god.
Mckay 认为他可以驾驭风暴中的闪电用来打开防护罩
Mckay figures he can harness
the storm's lightning to fire up the shield.
只用闪电?
Just lightning?
在此之前SG Team也曾经用过闪电为星际之门提供能量
SG teams have done it before to power a stargate.
毕竟星际之门和防护罩还是有很大不同的...
There's a big difference between a stargate...
我没有说你可以讲话了
I didn't say you could talk.
现在...
Now...
我需要运行一个子程序来构建一个
I need to run the subroutine that will convince
防护罩发生器的输入缓冲区
the input buffers in the shield generator
将原始的电能削弱成为可用的能量
to attenuate the raw electricity into usable power.
这个我只能在控制室里完成
I can only do that from the control room.
而Weir也将在那里输入她的口令
That's where Dr. Weir's codes come in.
好的
Yes.
只有主系统可以操作
Only primary systems are operating.
Sheppard必须修复另外一个发电机
Sheppard has to repair the other generator.
防护罩属于主系统
The shield's considered a primary system.
我们可以走了, 但我们必须现在就走
我是说现在
We're good to go, but we have to go now, I mean now.
我的意思是所有人, 所有你的人
I mean everybody, all your men.
为什么我的人也必须走?
What does that have to do with my men?
现在地下站已经被停用了
Now that the grounding station's been deactivated,
电流将会在导管中自由流动
electricity will be free to flow through the conduits
那将包括这个城市中的所有走廊
that line every corridor in the city.
这到底是个什么类型的计划?
What kind of a plan is that?
Rodney McKay类型的计划
A Rodney McKay kind of plan.
我们知道的也就是这些
It's all we've got.
而且我们只有一个地方可以去
And it leaves us only one place to go.
而Genii也将会去那里
Where the Genii will also be.
现在, 控制室和星际之门将会受到防御
Now, the control room and
stargate operations are shielded,
但城市的其它部分...
but the rest of the city...
一旦闪电开始击中...
Once the lightning starts to hit...
任何留在走廊中的人都会死
Anybody left in the hallways is as good as dead.
你怎么没有回答?
Why haven't you responded?
她在这儿, 司令官
She's here, Commander.
谁?
Who?
Teyla. 和另外两个人加入了Sheppard.
Teyla. She and two others have joined Sheppard.
为什么不早点报告?
Why wasn't this reported sooner?
迅速撤离到控制室
Fall back to the control room immediately.
她刚刚才走开
She's just out of my reach.
如果我有耐心的话...
If I am patient...
我在命令你
I gave you an order.
她丢下了我的父亲, 让他等死
She left my father for dead.
风暴已经降临了, 对我们来说城市已经不安全了
The storm is upon us. The city is no longer safe.
我不管
I don't care.
快回来
Fall back.
我向你发誓, 你父亲的仇一定会报的
You have my word. Your father will be avenged.
- 通过我
- Sora
- By me.
那些年轻的猎人们在飞船里安全么?
Will the young hunters in the jumper be safe?
空港是星际之门操作区的一部分
The jumper bay's part of stargate operations.
他们会得到保护的
They'll be protected.
他我们可能也该去那里
Then maybe that's where we should be headed.
如果防护罩在城市上空升起
Weir和McKay可能会因为Kolya而死
If the shield goes up over the city,
Weir and McKay are expendable to Kolya.
我们应该首先去占领控制室
We got to take the control room first.
他仅仅会因为他们没有用而杀了他们么？
Would he really kill them just because
they are of no further use to him?
不, 他会杀了他们来惩罚我
No, he'd kill them to punish me.
好, 现在的任务是...
Now, here's the deal...
我和Ford到控制室的楼梯下占好位置
Ford and I get into position,
just below the control room stairs.
Teyla和Beckett赶往空港
Teyla and Beckett head to the jumper bay.
我想和你并肩作战...
I intend to fight alongside you...
我也需要你和我一起作战
and I intend you to fight with us.
一旦你占据位置之后
Once you get in position,
将飞船开进星际之门所在的房间
lower the ship into the gate room,
亮出武器
open the weapons pods.
这将会分散他们的注意力, 我和Ford也就可以进去
That should create enough distraction
for Ford and me to go in.
我们夺回控制室, 然后升起防护罩
We take back the control room, get the shield up.
城市获救了
City's saved.
Weir和McKay也将获救
Weir and McKay saved.
我们一起度过剩下的日子
We take the rest of the day off.
听起来像是一个计划, 长官
Sounds like a plan, sir.
切换到二频道, 我们走
Stay on channel two. Let's move out.
我们不需要这个东西了
You're not going to need that thing.
见一个杀一个
Shoot to kill.
风越来越猛烈了
The winds are getting stronger
海浪也越来越高了
and the wave heights are growing.
我们需要继续拖延时间
We need to keep stalling.
为什么?
What for?
Sheppard还不知道在哪里
Major Sheppard is still out there.
如果你启动...
If you activate...
现在, McKay.
Now, McKay.
好了
It's done.
Weir博士, 现在我需要你输入你的密码
Dr. Weir, I need you to enter your code now.
好的, 当然
Yes, of course.
7, 9... 4, 2, 1
Seven, nine... Four, two, one.
继续
Yes?
0, 3, 2, 4, 5
Zero, three, two, four, five.
序列2?
And the second sequence?
我很高兴如果接下来的任务完成了...
I'll be glad when
this following-orders business is over...
丢掉它!
Drop it!
否则我杀了他
I'll kill him.
我不想这么快就杀了你
I would hate to kill you so quickly.
自从你生下来我就认识你了
I have known you for almost all your life.
你为什么要这么做?
Why are you doing this?
你留下他等死...
You left him to die...
你父亲杀了一个无辜的人
Your father killed an innocent.
是他把我们的行踪暴露给了幽灵
He alerted the wraith to our presence.
然后你就逃离了?
And you escaped.
如果我死于你手, Sora...
If I am to die by your hand, Sora...
那么至死我也相信
I die knowing there was nothing
我没有任何办法可以救Tyrus.
I could have done to have saved Tyrus.
我们就位了
We're in position.
有点不对劲
This isn't right.
什么?
What?
Teyla和Beckett应该会先到达空港
Teyla and Beckett should have
easily made it to the jumper bay first.
应该是他们在等我们
They should have been waiting for us.
Teyla, 你在哪里?
Teyla, what's your position?
Teyla?
这是我父亲的
This was my father's.
这是从他的父亲手里传下来的
It was handed down from his father.
如果你想以这种方式打假, Sora, 获胜的是我
If you want to fight this way, Sora, I will win.
你将不会为任何人报仇
You will have avenged no one.
那我们就来吧
We'll see.
启动防护罩
Engage the shield.
快完了
I'm almost finished.
一排巨浪正从西边逼近我们
A massive wave is approaching from the west.
如果没有防护罩...
Without the shield...
McKay!
已经有闪电击中北面的平台了
We're starting to get hits on the northern pier.
将电能导向走廊... 现在
Routing power to the corridor... Now.
现在
Now.
OK, 现在有一个问题
Okay, this is a problem.
什么?
What?
瞧, 我告诉过你
这只是一个很少机会成功的尝试
Look, I told you this was
a long shot from the beginning.
洪水已经漫上北面和西面的平台了
We already have serious flooding
on the north and west piers.
这没有用
城市的导管无法处理这种类型的原始能量
It's no use. The city conduits
can't handle this kind of raw power.
有能量被送往防护罩发生器么?
Is any power getting to the shield generator?
完全没有
Nominal amounts. Nowhere near enough.
你是说这会奏效
You said this would work.
我不知道你注意到没有,
我并不是一个自大的人
I don't know if you noticed or not,
but I am extremely arrogant man
是谁认为他的计划会工作
who tends to think all of his plans will work.
白痴!
Idiot!
Hey, 这至多只是一个很少机会成功的尝试
Hey, this was a long shot at best.
要不然我们为什么会疏散整个城市?
Why else would we evacuate the city?
如果这不能奏效
It was always our intention to dial out
我们会义无反顾的拨号出去
in case this didn't work.
Atlantis坚持不了多久了
Within minutes, Atlantis will fail.
你可以离开并存活下来
You can leave and survive,
要不你就将跟这座城市一起沉没
or you can go down with the city.
你自己选择
You choose.
我们没有获取足够的能量来开启防护罩
We're just not getting enough power
to the shield generators.
你真的愿意把你的人的生命
Are you really going to sacrifice the lives
寄托于这座城市不会完全毁灭
of all of your men on the off-chance that this city
这一极小的机会上么?
won't be completely destroyed?
打开星际之门
Open the stargate.
开始疏散剩下的人
Start evacuating the remaining men.
你做出了正确的决定
You're making the right decision.
你们要和我们一起走
You're coming with us.
什么?
What?
你们要为你们所做的一切为Genii人付出赔偿
You'll both serve the Genii
as payment for what you've done.
噢, 为了我们做的什么?
Oh, for what we've done?
计划修改
Change of plan.
你去救McKay.
You got McKay.
认真地说, 这是不是一个好主意
Seriously, this is a bad idea.
你也看到了, 我的机会最后发生了什么
You saw what happened to my last plan.
这并不是...
This is not what...
你哪也去不了
You're not going anywhere.
如果你不放开她, 我就会开枪打你
I will shoot you if you don't let her go.
冒着伤害Weir博士的风险?
And risk hurting Dr. Weir?
我并没有瞄准她
I'm not aiming at her.
找到Teyla和Beckett. 一定要找到他们
Find Teyla and Beckett. Make sure that's all of them.
非常抱歉, 我不得不...
Sorry about that. I had to...
你还好吧?
You okay?
不好
No.
会好的. 来吧
You will be. Come on.
等等! 你要做什么?
Wait! What are you doing?
我想我要启动防护罩
I thought I'd activate the shield and save the day.
你还在想什么?
You got something else in mind?
Teyla和Beckett仍然不知道在哪里
Teyla and Beckett are still out there.
跟踪系统不工作了
Tracking system's down.
有一个海啸正朝城市而来, 中尉
There's a tsunami headed towards the city, lieutenant.
在两分半钟之后, 我们就都会死了
In two and a half minutes, they're dead.
那我就给他们两分钟
Then we give them two minutes.
这不是你父亲想要的
This is not what your father would have wanted.
我们本来应该结成同盟...
Our people were destined to be allies...
Teyla和Beckett, 回到控制室来
Teyla and Beckett, fall back to the control room.
该结束了... 现在!
This must end... now!
那就结束吧
Then end it.
没有时间了
There's no more time.
我们要么失去他们, 要么就失去整个城市
We either lose them or we lose the city.
Rodney, 启动!
Rodney, go!
正在启动
Going!
发生什么事了?
What's happening?
启动了, 必须积攒足够的能量来启动防护罩
It's working, It just needs to build up
enough power for the shield to activate.
等一下
Wait for it.
Carson.
Rodney.
你正巧看到了这个结局, huh?
You're just in time to see how this ends, huh?
现在
Now.
干得好, Rodney.
Nice work, Rodney.
你曾经怀疑过我么?
Did you ever doubt me?
是的, 有好多次
Yes, several times.
我看到你找到了一个新朋友, Teyla.
I see you've made a new friend, Teyla.
你将会怎样对她?
What do you want to do with her?
现在还不知道
I don't know yet.
在接下来的日子里我们会一直看着她
We'll keep her locked up for the time being.
也许把她放回Genii可以帮助消除我们之间的紧张情绪
Maybe releasing her back to the Genii
would help ease tension between us.
你真是太乐观了. 你知道么?
You're extremely optimistic. You know that?
你这样认为么?
You think so?
每个人都回来了?
Everyone getting back okay?
看起来是这样
Looks like it.
我们的城市怎么样了?
How fares our city?
嗯, 我们已经开始抽排底层的水了
Well, we've begun pumping out the lower levels
在东边的平台, 被水淹的那个
of the east pier, which was flooded.
有一些结构性的损坏
不过都不太严重
There is structural damage, nothing too serious.
Beckett有轻微的脑震荡
Beckett's suffered from a minor concussion.
我的意思是, 看这个, 我自己干的
I mean, look at this. I had to do this myself.
在好的方面, 我已经进行了24小时以来第一次正式的进餐了
Still, on the bright side,
I've had my first decent meal in 24 hours,
因此总体来说, 我想说我们都还好
so all things considered, I would say we are just fine.
你说这种事情每20年就会发生一次, 是么?
You say these things happen every 20 years, right?
那是他们说的
That's what they tell us.
那距离下一次还有多久?
How far in advance can we book days off?